racecarthings.com 2017-11-18

# Privacy Policy - RaceCarThings.com

The following privacy policy covers all of the websites of RaceCarThings and its subsidiaries and affiliates websites, the Mobile Services (as defined below) or desktop application services, software, or other materials or services made available on, from, or through the websites (collectively, the “Website(s)”). This policy does not, however, apply to entities that RaceCarThings.com does not own or control, such as applications and websites using Facebook Platform. If you create a RaceCarThings.com account using Facebook or another third party social media service, or if you link your RaceCarThings.com account with any of these third party services, we may share your information with these third party services. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by the Website(s). Please read this policy. If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us.

By using the Website(s) you understand and agree that RaceCarThings.com is providing a platform for you to post content, including photos, comments and other materials (“User Submissions”) to the Website(s) and to share User Submissions publicly. This means that other users may search for, see, use, or share any of your User Submissions that you make publicly available through the Website(s), consistent with the terms and conditions of this privacy policy and RaceCarThings.com’s Terms of Use

#### **Collection and Use of Aggregated Information**

RaceCarThings.com creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns. These aggregated statistics are used internally to better provide services to users of the Website(s) and may also be provided to advertisers, sponsors, and partners but they contain no individual personal information and cannot be used to gather such information. This allows RaceCarThings.com’s advertisers, partners, and sponsors to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs.

#### **Ownership of Information**

RaceCarThings.com is the sole owner of the information collected on the Website(s) which includes:

  * _Your username, password and e-mail address when you register for an account on a Website._
  * _Profile information that you provide for your user profile (e.g., first and last name, picture, phone number). This information allows RaceCarThings.com to help you or others be “found” on the Website(s)._
  * _User Submissions that you post to the Website(s)._
  * _Communications between you and RaceCarThings.com. For example, RaceCarThings.com may send you emails related to the Website(s) (e.g., account verification, changes/updates to features of the Website(s), technical and security notices). Note that you may not opt out of these e-mails._
  * _RaceCarThings.com may offer certain services that are available via a mobile device or app, including (i) the ability to upload User Submissions to the Website(s) via a mobile device, (ii) the ability to browse the Website(s) from a mobile device and (iii) the ability to access certain features through an application downloaded and installed on a mobile device (collectively, the ”Mobile Services“). If you use the Mobile Services, RaceCarThings.com may store information regarding your mobile device, including your device type and operating system, the advertising ID of your mobile device, location services (if you grant permission), or in other applications as permitted by the functionality of such mobile device. In addition, RaceCarThings.com may access, collect, monitor, store on your device, and/or remotely store one or more “device identifiers.” Device identifiers are small data files or similar data structures stored on or associated with your mobile device, which uniquely identify your mobile device. A device identifier may be data stored in connection with the device hardware, data stored in connection with the device’s operating system or other software, or data sent to the device by RaceCarThings.com. A device identifier may deliver information to RaceCarThings.com or to a third party partner about how you browse and use the Website(s) and may help RaceCarThings.com or others provide reports or personalized content and ads. Some features of the Website(s) may not function properly if use or availability of device identifiers is impaired or disabled._

#### **How We Use Your Information**

RaceCarThings.com uses the information that you provide, or that RaceCarThings.com collects, to provide RaceCarThings.com’s services and features to you; to operate, maintain, and enhance the Website(s); to measure and improve the Website(s); to provide you with customer support; as well as to track user-generated content and users to comply as a service provider with the DMCA and other applicable laws. RaceCarThings.com uses the information to prevent potentially illegal activities. These efforts may on occasion result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions for some users. RaceCarThings.com may contact you with announcements related to the Website(s) from time to time. You may opt out of all communications except essential updates on your account.

RaceCarThings.com doesn’t share your information with advertisers without your consent. RaceCarThings.com allows advertisers to choose the characteristics of users who will see their advertisements and RaceCarThings.com may use any of the non-personally identifiable attributes it has collected (including information you may have decided not to show to other users, such as your birth year or other sensitive personal information or preferences) to select the appropriate audience for those advertisements.  Even though RaceCarThings.com does not share your information with advertisers without your consent, when you click on or otherwise interact with an advertisement there is a possibility that the advertiser may place a cookie in your browser or the advertising ID for the Mobile Services and note that it meets the criteria they selected.

RaceCarThings.com may share User Submissions and your information (including but not limited to, information from cookies, log files, device identifiers, location data, and usage data) with businesses that are legally part of the same group of companies that RaceCarThings.com is part of, or that become part of that group (“Affiliates”). Affiliates may use this information to help provide, understand, and improve the Website(s) (including by providing analytics) and Affiliates’ own services (including by providing you with better and more relevant experiences); however, these Affiliates will honor the choices you make about who can see your photos.

#### **Content and Metadata**

The Website(s) are intended to share Content with others. “Content” includes the text, graphics, photos, sounds, music, videos, audiovisual combinations, and other materials you may view on, access through, or contribute to the Website(s).  If you do not want us to store metadata associated with Website(s) you share on the Website(s) (such as photos), please remove the metadata before uploading the Content.

#### **Exclusions**

This privacy policy does not apply to any information collected by RaceCarThings.com other than information collected through the Website(s). This privacy policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information you provide to RaceCarThings.com through the Website(s) or through any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, Content or other information posted to any public areas of the Website(s), such as comments, any ideas for new products or modifications to existing products, and other unsolicited submissions (collectively, “Unsolicited Information”). All Unsolicited Information shall be deemed to be non-confidential and RaceCarThings.com shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, distribute and exploit such Unsolicited Information without limitation or attribution.

#### **Comments**

In order to enhance their use of the Website(s), users can choose to leave comments on particular articles of interest. RaceCarThings.com does not endorse these comments as they are opinions of users not associated with RaceCarThings.com or its employees.

#### **Mailing List**

RaceCarThings.com may launch a mailing list for some or all of the Website(s). In order to sign up to receive regular emails, newsletters and the like from a mailing list from one of the Website(s), users must submit information including, without limitation, a valid email address and demographic information such as location and interests. This information will be used in anonymous, aggregate form only in order to assess general user interest in various internal and third party products and services, and your personal and contact information will not be passed to any other organization. Users who choose to sign up for a mailing list will receive regular emails from the site, including new articles added to the site as well as emails from third party site sponsors. If you do not wish to receive emails from third party advertisers, do not sign up for the mailing list.

#### **Public Forums**

The Website(s) make chat rooms and message boards available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

#### **Cookies**

Some of RaceCarThings.com’s business partners (for example, advertisers) may use cookies on the Website(s) or advertising IDs for the Mobile Services (collectively, “cookies”). However, RaceCarThings.com has no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by RaceCarThings.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

In addition, the Website(s) use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”).  Google Analytics and RaceCarThings.com’s business partners use cookies to help them analyze how users use the Website(s). The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Website(s)  (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google and RaceCarThings.com’s business partners will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Website(s), compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage.  Google and RaceCarThings.com’s business partners may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s or RaceCarThings.com’s business partners’ behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.  You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, or by enabling the Do Not Track settings in your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Website(s).  By using this Web site, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google and RaceCarThings.com’s business partners in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

#### **Third Party Advertising**

The ads appearing on Website(s) are delivered to users by third party advertisers including Google, among others. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please click here. This site allows third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you and other Internet users visit. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this site and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third-party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org. Users may opt out of behavioral targeting through the opt-out link HERE

RaceCarThings.com’s sites participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising within advertising units that link to<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

#### **Log Files**

Like most standard website servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. We may use a tracking utility that uses log files to analyze user movement.

#### **Legal Disclosures**

RaceCarThings.com may need to disclose personal information when required by law or legal process.  RaceCarThings.com may also share information when it has a good-faith belief that such action is necessary: to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on any of the Website(s); to prevent fraud or other illegal activity; to prevent imminent bodily harm; or, to protect RaceCarThings.com and users from people violating these Terms.

#### **Business Transitions**

In the event RaceCarThings.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of a portion of its assets, , or if RaceCarThings.com declares bankruptcy, RaceCarThings.com may transfer your personal information  as part of the assets transferred.

#### **Links**

The Website(s) contain links to other sites. Please be aware that RaceCarThings.com has no control over and is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. RaceCarThings.com has no control over and is not responsible for the privacy policies or content of such sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by RaceCarThings.com.

#### **Notification of Changes**

Whenever RaceCarThings.com changes its privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and other places we deem appropriate.

#### **Violations of this Policy**

RaceCarThings.com will terminate your access to the Website(s) if, under appropriate circumstances, RaceCarThings.com determines you violated this privacy policy.

#### **California Privacy Rights**

YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS – California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits members of the Website(s) who are California residents to request certain information regarding the disclosure of any personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)racecarthings.com.

#### **How Should a User Contact RaceCarThings.com LLC?**

** ** If you suspect that RaceCarThings.com has handled your information in a manner that does not comply with this Privacy Policy, please contact us by e-mailing to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)racecarthings.com.

_This privacy policy is effective as of September 1, 2014._
